我们来谈谈图像如何形成的几何形状。所有图像都以光线开始
Let’s talk about the geometry of how images are formed. All images start with light coming
来自某些光源;也许是太阳，也许是天花板上的室内灯
from some source of illumination; perhaps the sun, perhaps indoor lights in the ceiling
建筑物的光线反射出世界上的物体。其中一些反映出来
of a building and that light reflects off objects in the world. Some of that reflected
光在我们眼中结束。反射有两种类型。有镜子般的反射
light ends up in our eyes. There are two types of reflection. There is the mirror-like reflection
我们称之为镜面反射，并且存在漫反射或无光泽表面的反射，
we call specular reflection and there is the reflection from a diffuse or matte surface,
这被称为朗伯反射。
which is called Lambertian reflection.
大多数表面是镜面反射和朗伯反射的混合。但无论如何
Most surfaces are a mixture of specular reflection and Lambertian reflection. But irrespective
在发生的那种反射中，我们从光源反射光
of the sort of reflection that’s occurring, we have light from a light source reflecting
关闭物体，其中一些光线将进入我们的眼睛。我们来看看这个
off objects and some of those light rays are going to enter our eyes. Let’s look at this
在图形表示中。
in a graphical representation.
我们再一次观察现场。我们有一个三维物体
Once again, we have our observer of the scene. We have a three-dimensional object in the
世界，我们将考虑在特定对象的几个点上发生的事情。
world and we’re going to consider what happens at just a few points on that particular object.
所以我们首先需要的是光源。
So the first thing we need is a source of light.
我们打开太阳，现在将要发生的是光将从中反射出来
We turn on the sun and what’s going to happen now is light is going to be reflected from
太阳在许多这些点和一些光线将进入
the sun at a number of these points and some of those light rays are going to enter the
观察者的眼睛。当我们看一个三维雕像
eyes of the observer. When we look at a three-dimensional statue
无论是通过相机还是用我们自己的眼睛，我们都会体验到非常生动的感觉
like this either through a camera or with our own eyes, we experience a very vivid and
那个物体的清晰图像。但是，如果我只是在这里拿一张纸而且它正在接收
crisp image of that object. But if I simply hold up a piece of paper here and it is receiving
从雕像中反射出来的光，无论我看多么努力或有多紧密
light that’s reflected off the statue, then no matter how hard or how closely I look at
在这篇文章中，没有形成图像的概念。我们需要整理光明
this paper, there is no concept of image being formed on here. We need to organize the light
光线，离开雕像，以获得清晰的图像。
rays, which are leaving the statue in order to get a crisp image.
那么让我们以图形方式看待这个问题。我们有一个图像平面，一张纸
So let’s look at this problem graphically. We have an image plane, the piece of paper
我刚刚举起，如果我考虑那个图像平面上的任何特定点，那么
that I just held up and if I consider any particular point on that image plane, the
落在任何一个点上的光可能来自任意数量的点
light that’s falling on any single point could have come from any number of points
在三维物体上。发生的事情是来自所有这些点的光
on the three-dimensional object. What’s happened is the light from all of those points
正在混淆，所以如果我只是拿起一张纸就没有连贯的图像了
is being mixed up so that if I just hold up a piece of paper no coherent image will be
形成于此。
formed on that.
我们需要做的是以某种方式订购光线和最简单的思考方式
What we need to do is to order the light rays in some way and the simplest way to think
关于这样做是为了在图像平面的前面放一个不透明的平面并钻一个
about doing this is to put an opaque plane in front of the image plane and to drill a
小洞里面。这是一种被称为针孔相机的配置。
small hole in it. This is a configuration that’s referred to as a pinhole camera.
这样做是为了对离开物体上的点的光线进行排序
What this does is order the rays that are leaving the points on the object and it causes
在图像平面上形成的倒置（即倒置的图像）。这种方法
an inverted (that is an upside-down image) to be formed on the image plane. This approach
成像被称为针孔相机。有时它被称为相机暗箱，它是
to imaging is called a pinhole camera. Sometimes it’s called a camera obscura and it’s
自古以来就为人所知。
been known since ancient times.
这张照片显示了一座建筑物，墙上钻有一个小洞，发生了什么
This picture shows a building with a small hole drilled in its wall and what’s happening
就是有一个外面明亮太阳的图像被投射在内墙上
is that there is an image of the bright sun outside is being cast on the interior wall
建筑物。
of the building.
以下是我从网上下载的针孔相机图像的一些示例。人
Here are some examples of pinhole camera images that I’ve downloaded from the web. People
他们已经观察过这些图像，或许它们已经进入了一个黑暗的房间里
have observed these images perhaps they’ve been inside a darkened room, there’s been
外面一个明亮的场景，一个阳光灿烂的日子，盲人可能还有一个洞
a bright scene outside, a bright sunny day and there’s been perhaps a hole on the blind
或窗户覆盖，并导致外部世界的形象投射在
or window covering and that has caused an image of the outside world to be cast on the
壁。
wall.
现在回想一下前一个例子，这个图像是倒置的。所以在左手
Now recall from the previous example that this image is inverted. So in the left-hand
图像，这个人把他们的相机翻过来，你可以看到一个电动牙刷
image, the person like turned their camera upside-down and you can see an electric toothbrush
从顶部悬挂和右手图像，你可以看到针孔的事实
hanging from the top and in the right-hand image, you can see the fact that the pinhole
事实上，图像是倒置的。这是一个非常非常大的针孔相机的例子。这个
image is in fact inverted. Here is an example of a very, very large pinhole camera. This
这是一个惊人的项目，发生在2008年一个废弃的飞机库里
was an amazing project that happened in a disused aircraft hangar back in 2008. On the
离开时，我们可以看到一群人站在图像平面前。那是在哪里
left, we can see a bunch of people standing in front of the image plane. That’s where
来自针孔摄像机的图像已经投射，在右侧，你可以看到
the image from the pinhole camera has been cast and on the right-hand side, you can see
他们努力实际拍摄这些图像，以便制作出非常非常大的作品
them endeavouring to actually capture that image so they made a very, very large piece
电影，一个非常大的负片，他们会把它靠在墙上暴露
of film, a very large negative and they’re going to put it up against the wall and expose
它使用这个针孔相机拍摄图像。
it and capture an image using this pinhole camera.
因此，快速了解针孔相机会发生什么。光线离开各种各样
So, a quick refresher on what happens with a pinhole camera. Rays of light leave various
对象上的点。它们都穿过针孔并投下一张倒置的图像
points on the object. They all pass through the pinhole and cast an upside-down image
我们称之为图像平面。
on what we call the image plane.
这个针孔相机的几何形状实际上很容易描述。我们会考虑
The geometry of this pinhole camera is actually very simple to describe. We’ll consider
该物体距离针孔平面和图像平面的距离为Z.
that the object is at a distance Z away from the plane of the pinhole and the image plane
是远离针孔平面的距离F（焦距F）。
is a distance F (F for focal distance) away from the plane of the pinhole.
然后，如果对象的高度为Y，则图像的高度为y，这些是两个
Then if the height of the object is Y, the height of the image is y and these are two
类似三角形。所以在这里写关系很容易。它很简单
similar triangles. So it’s very easy to write the relationship over here. It simply
来自我们有两个相似三角形的事实。我们也可以做同样的事情
comes from the fact that we’ve got two similar triangles. We can also do the same thing for
水平面。我们引入符号X表示距离页面的距离
the horizontal plane. We introduce the symbol X for the distance out of the page of the
我们正在查看的对象和x在图像平面中沿着墙的距离。
object that we’re looking at and x for the distance along the wall in the image plane.
我们可以再次编写来自查看两个相似三角形的方程式。所以
We can again write the equations that come from looking at two similar triangles. So
这个图像形成过程用坐标X，Y和Z映射世界中的一个点
this image formation process maps a point in the world with coordinates X, Y and Z to
图像平面上坐标为x和y的点。我们可以重新排列那些方程式
a point on the image plane whose coordinates are x and y. We can rearrange those equations
以这种方式。
in this fashion.
因此，如果x现在根据真实世界坐标X和Z，并且类似于y。所以这就是
So if x now in terms of the real world coordinates X and Z and similarly for y. So this is what
我们称之为预测。它将三维量X，Y，Z投影成二维量，
we call a projection. It projects a three-dimensional quantity X, Y, Z into a two-dimensional quantity,
x和y。它是三维和二维之间的映射。
x and y. It is a mapping between three dimensions and two dimensions.
这被称为透视投影。这是该过程的数学基础
This referred to as perspective projection. This is the mathematical basis for the process
我们称之为透视投影。透视投影的结果是
that we’d call perspective projection. A consequence of perspective projection is that
没有独特的逆。如果我在现实世界中有一个物体的图像，那么那里
there is no unique inverse. If I have an image of the object in the real world then there
是可能导致该图像的无限数量的可能对象。它可能是一个
are an infinite number of possible objects that could cause that image. It could be a
靠近我的小物体，或者它可能是一个远离我的大物体
small object that’s close to me or it could be a large object that’s further away from
我。
me.
其中一个方面已经从根本上消失了。从二维图像，我们不能
One of the dimensions has been fundamentally lost. From a two-dimensional image, we cannot
恢复这第三个维度。现在，在我们的大脑中，我们使用了很多技巧来尝试
recover this third dimension. Now, in our brains, we use a lot of tricks to try and
恢复第三个维度。我们对这个结构有所了解
recover that third dimension. We know something about the structure of the
世界。我们对物体的大小有所了解。所以，如果我们看到什么看起来像一个小
world. We know something about the size of objects. So if we see what looks like a small
我们认为“不，不，不，这可能是一个更远的人。”
person we think “No, no, no, it’s probably a large person who is further away.”
因此，恢复第三个维度从根本上是不可能的，但还有其他信息
So to recover the third dimension is fundamentally impossible but there is other information
我们可以带来恢复它。
that we can bring to bear to recover it.